Wedyan Aloufi

FrontEnd Javascript Developer Riyadh, Saudi Arabia wedyaan-aloufi@hotmail.com +966 53 249 8325

linkedin: wedyan

A skilled Front-End JavaScript Developer specializing in building engaging, user-friendly, and responsive websites. Proficient in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, with the ability to transform designs into functional, visually appealing web experiences across various devices and browsers.

Winner of 4th Prize in Qoranthon 2024 out of 1800 participants (300+ teams) from 42 countries.

Work Experience

Support Engineer

Indorse company - Saudi Arabia August 2024 -Present

My responsibilities:

- Performed system testing and identified issues to ensure optimal performance..
- Raised and tracked tickets in Jira, ensuring timely follow-up and resolution until closure..
- Created detailed user manuals to support end-user understanding and system usage.
- API Development and Integration.
- Experience in automated testing using Postman.
- Familiarity with tools like Swagger for documenting APIs.
- Skills in troubleshooting API errors and understanding HTTP status codes
- → System Testing, JIRA, Microsoft Word, Postman, API Development and Integration, API Testing.

Web Developer

Sababa Foundation - Saudi Arabia November 2022 - March 2023

My responsibilities:

- Optimized the website's front-end for efficiency, scalability, and performance.
- Optimized website performance for speed, and accessibility.
- Regularly updated and patched software to maintain website security.
- Conducted regular site maintenance, including backups and content updates.
- → WordPress, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery

Freelancer

Freelance - Online

June 2022 - November 2022

Worked full-time as a freelancer with various clients.

My responsibilities:

- Explained technical concepts in a way that clients can understand.
- Prioritized tasks to ensure that both projects progress smoothly.
- Identified and resolved any technical issues that arise during development.
- Adapted to changes in project scope or client requirements.
- → Reactjs, Bootstrap, WordPress

Mobile Application Developer

Taibah University - Saudi Arabia February 2022 to June 2022

- I developed a mobile application for agriculture merchants under my final graduation project.
- → Flutter, Dart

Education

Bachelor in Computer science

Taibah University - Saudi Arabia September 2018 to June 2022

Skills

Technical Skills:

JavaScript, React.js, Next.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Git, WordPress, Adobe Photoshop, Figma.

Soft Skills:

Communication, Teamwork, Critical Thinking, Problem-Solving.

Certifications/Licenses

Learning Next.js

May 2024

Next-JS Course from Udemy

Credential ID : UC-MVMWY36V | See credential

Building Modern Projects with React

May 2024

React-JS Course from Udemy

Credential ID: UC-MVMWY36V | See credential

React-JS

September 2024

Next-JS Course from LinkedIn Learning

Credential ID: UC-WVWWZ36V | See credential

JavaScript Course from Zero to Expert

May 2024

JavaScript Course from Zero to Expert from Udemy. Credential ID : UC-MVMWZ36V | See credential

JavaScript Camp (200 Hours)

July 2023 - September 2023. JavaScript Camp (200 Hours) from **Tuwaiq Academy** <u>See credential</u>

Build Responsive Real-World Websites with HTML and CSS

November 2022

Build Responsive Real-World Websites with HTML and CSS, a Course from Udemy. Credential ID: UC-MVMWZ36V | See credential

Front End Development

July 2022

Front-End Development from the Ministry of Communications and Information Technology See credential